{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Edward J. Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Martin P. Roberts","Alan T. Davis","Roger B. Lewis"],"question":"Who was Captain of the Titanic on her maiden voyage?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"1 year","incorrectAnswers":["1 month","1 week","1 day"],"question":"Two rats can become the progenitors of 15,000 rats in less than","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Birch Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Oak Tree","Maple Tree","Elm Tree"],"question":"Which type of tree is known for its silvery white bark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Consumer Spending","incorrectAnswers":["Personal Spending","Investment Spending","Big Spending"],"question":"In economics, what is the term for the amount of money that individuals spend on goods and services?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Lilywhites","incorrectAnswers":["The Blades","The Blues","The Hornets"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Preston North End?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎Francisco Goya","incorrectAnswers":["Vincent van Gogh","Paul Cézanne","Eugène Delacroix"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Third of May\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"existence","incorrectAnswers":["a branch of soil science that studies the influence of soil on life","grasses","the scientific study of muscles"],"question":"What is Ontology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Elisha Otis","incorrectAnswers":["Marshall Rivet","Thomas Edison","Maxwell Hoff"],"question":"Who Invented The Elevator?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Open Championship","incorrectAnswers":["Le Mans 24 Hours","The Copa Libertadores","The IAAF World Championships"],"question":"Which of these is a competition in Golf?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["Cocteau Twins","Lostprophets","The Kinks"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Stairway to Heaven'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["String","Wind","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a marimba?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George Washington ","incorrectAnswers":["Chester Arthur","Ulysses S. Grant","Millard Fillmore"],"question":"Who was the 1st president of the USA, in term during the period 1789–1797?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"44","incorrectAnswers":["22","66","88"],"question":"What is the lowest common multiple of 22 and 44?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Couscous","incorrectAnswers":["Ndolé","Gallo Pinto","Rösti"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with The Middle East?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Nashville SC","incorrectAnswers":["Nashville Canucks","Nashville Padres","Nashville Thunder"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Nashville?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Douglas Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","H. G. Wells","Arthur C. Clarke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Smallpox","incorrectAnswers":["Polio","Influenza","Measles"],"question":"For what disease was the first successful vaccine developed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Tanzania","Malta","Brazil"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Prambanan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Monica and Ross","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel and Joey","Phoebe and Chandler","Monica and Chandler"],"question":"On the TV show Friends, which characters do Courtney Cox and David Schwimmer play?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Meg Cabot","incorrectAnswers":["Stephenie Meyer","Philip K. Dick","Brandon Sanderson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Princess Diaries'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A labour","incorrectAnswers":["A covey","A watch","A nest"],"question":"What is the word for a group of moles?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Joni Mitchell","incorrectAnswers":["Leonard Cohen","Elton John","Tom Waits"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled \"Blue\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Nineteenth Hole","incorrectAnswers":["Bird Bath","Eagles Rest","The greenhouse"],"question":"What popular golf term refers to a bar or pub at the end of a golf course?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Chronicles of Narnia","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Divergent","The Hunger Games"],"question":"In which book series would you find the character of 'Aslan'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bloody Mary","incorrectAnswers":["Mimosa","Screwdriver","Tequila Sunrise"],"question":"What cocktail includes tabasco sauce and is commonly consumed for breakfast?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["6","8","5"],"question":"How many teats does a cow have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"On the Origin of Species","incorrectAnswers":["Germinal","Eine Geschichte des Universums in 100 Sternen","Madame Bovary"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'When we look to the individuals of the same variety or sub‐variety of our older cultivated plants and animals, one of the first points which strikes us, is, that they generally differ much more from each other, than do the individuals of any one species or variety in a state of nature.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Quetzalcoatl","incorrectAnswers":["Huitzilopochtli","Tlaloc","Tezcatlipoca"],"question":"What is the name of the Aztec feathered serpent god?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Ice Hockey","Soccer"],"question":"Which sport is played at Roland-Garros?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Led Zeppelin","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which band was Bill Wyman a member of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Edward VIII","incorrectAnswers":["George IV","Edward IV","William II"],"question":"Who was the monarch of The United Kingdom during the time period 1936-1936?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Return of the King","incorrectAnswers":["Life, the Universe and Everything","The Mysterious Island","A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Pippin looked out from the shelter of Gandalf's coat.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vilnius","incorrectAnswers":["Stockholm","Majuro","Cairo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Lithuania?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Arnold Schwarzenegger","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Lee","Anthony Hopkins","Tom Hanks"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Batman & Robin and Predator?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Swimming","incorrectAnswers":["Track and Field","Gymnastics","Figure Skating"],"question":"The 100-meter butterfly and 100-meter freestyle are both events in what Olympic sport?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kit","incorrectAnswers":["A Kitten","A Pup","A Caterpillar"],"question":"What is a baby weasel known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Emily Brontë","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","H. Rider Haggard","Percy Bysshe Shelley"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Wuthering Heights'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"ends or final causes","incorrectAnswers":["ticks and mites","bryophytes","mental processes in living creatures"],"question":"What is Teleology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nairobi","incorrectAnswers":["Managua","Kampala","Georgetown"],"question":"What is the capital city of Kenya?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Karate","Kickboxing","Judo"],"question":"With Which Sport Would You Associate A Lonsdale Belt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A screenwriter develops a relationship with a faded film star determined to make a return.","incorrectAnswers":["An insurance salesman discovers his whole life is actually a reality TV show.","A woman tries to warn anyone who will listen about the merciless space predators that attacked her.","A Marine observes the effects of war on his fellow recruits from their boot camp training to fighting in a war."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Sunset Blvd.?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["United Kingdom","Australia","United States"],"question":"In which country is the city of Dublin?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["France","The United States","Germany"],"question":"What was the first country to legalize trade unions, in the 19th century?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Baker","incorrectAnswers":["Chef","Waiter","Butcher"],"question":"What is the English translation of the Spanish word 'panadero'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Humiliated and Insulted'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rice","incorrectAnswers":["Quinoa","Bulgar wheat","Barley"],"question":"What is the grain used to make La Bandera, a traditional dish in the Dominican Republic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Seattle Kraken","incorrectAnswers":["Seattle Indians","Seattle Sharks","Seattle Wizards"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Seattle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","China","Russia"],"question":"Which country blew up a Greenpeace ship in New Zealand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Amadeus","incorrectAnswers":["The Killing Fields","A Passage to India","Places in the Heart"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1984?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Francis II","incorrectAnswers":["Charles V","Frederick III","Maximilian I"],"question":"Who was the last ruler of the Holy Roman Empire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1978","incorrectAnswers":["1972","1984","1990"],"question":"In which year was the first “test tube baby” conceived using IVF?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Othello","incorrectAnswers":["Hamlet","Macbeth","Julius Caesar"],"question":"Which Shakespeare title character is summoned by the Duke of Venice to help him deal with the threat of a Turkish attack?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"15","incorrectAnswers":["21","25","20"],"question":"How many points win a game in badminton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malta","incorrectAnswers":["Uzbekistan","Afghanistan","Comoros"],"question":"Valletta is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Jose Eathquakes","incorrectAnswers":["San Jose Bengals","San Jose Heat","San Jose Hawks"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in San Jose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Black","White"],"question":"In The Matrix, which pill did Neo take?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Bering Strait ","incorrectAnswers":["Malacca Strait","Strait of Hormuz","Strait of Magellan"],"question":"Which Strait Separates Alaska From Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Funafuti","incorrectAnswers":["Sana'a","Manama","Kigali"],"question":"What is the capital city of Tuvalu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gregory Peck","incorrectAnswers":["Anthony Perkins","James Cagney","Jean Pierre Leaud"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Atticus Finch in To Kill a Mockingbird?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Geoffrey Chaucer","incorrectAnswers":["William Shakespeare","William Wordsworth","Bede"],"question":"Who wrote the \"Canterbury Tales\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Andy Warhol ","incorrectAnswers":["Jackson Pollock","Gertrude Stein","Aaron Copland"],"question":"Who is the American artist who uses Campbell's Soup cans in his pop art?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Sailboat racing","incorrectAnswers":["Baseball","Volleyball","Golf"],"question":"In which sport is the America's Cup awarded? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jack","incorrectAnswers":["A Drake","A Tiercel","A Buck"],"question":"What would you call a male mule?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["Maine","Washington","Florida"],"question":"Which US state is home to Muir Woods, a national monument that contains giant redwood trees?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Amsterdam","incorrectAnswers":["Ljubljana","Brussels","Groningen"],"question":"What is the capital city of Netherlands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Flax","incorrectAnswers":["Sunflower","Hemp","Wheat"],"question":"Linen is obtained from the fibers of what plant?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Elton John","Usher","Kylie Minogue"],"question":"Whose Autobiography Was Entitled 'Moonwalk'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The Netherlands ","incorrectAnswers":["Belgium","Sweden","Spain"],"question":"KLM Is The National Airline Of Which Country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Norway","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Germany","Northern Ireland"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Bryggen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Master and Commander","incorrectAnswers":["Gone With the Wind","Heart of Darkness","The Thin Man"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Stephen Maturin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Monaco","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","Sweden","Switzerland"],"question":"On April 19, 1956, Grace Kelly had a storybook wedding with Prince Rainier of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem Delivered","incorrectAnswers":["Inferno","Metamorphoses","Pan Tadeusz"],"question":"In which book does 'Godfrey of Bouillon' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tongue","incorrectAnswers":["Nose","Anus","Ears"],"question":"What does a snake use to smell with?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple ","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Plum","Banana"],"question":"What Type Of Fruit Is A Russet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Natural","incorrectAnswers":["Field of Dreams","Bull Durham","A League of Their Own"],"question":"Robert Redford uses a homemade bat called Wonderboy in which baseball movie?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A baker","incorrectAnswers":["A tailor","A carpenter","A chef"],"question":"What occupation is represented by the French word 'boulanger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"A Typhoon","incorrectAnswers":["A Hurricane","A Cyclone","A Tornado"],"question":"What is the term for a tropical storm that occurs in the Pacific?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"A martini. Shaken, not stirred.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Elementary, my dear Watson.\"","\"Carpe diem. Seize the day, boys. Make your lives extraordinary.\"","\"Go ahead, make my day.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Goldfinger'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Paradise Lost","incorrectAnswers":["The Odyssey","Beowulf","The Divine Comedy"],"question":"In which epic poem by John Milton does Satan plot against Adam and Eve?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Plum ","incorrectAnswers":["Cherry","Peach","Raspberry"],"question":"What type of fruit is a damson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","New Zealand","United States"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Vancouver?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aerosmith","incorrectAnswers":["The Velvet Underground","The Everly Brothers","Rage Against the Machine"],"question":"Steven Tyler Is Lead Vocalist With Which Rock Band","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jodie Foster","incorrectAnswers":["Geena Davis","Laura Dern","Bette Midler"],"question":"Who won the 1991 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Clarice Starling in The Silence of the Lambs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Ribbon pasta","Stuffed pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is orecchiette?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mexico ","incorrectAnswers":["China","France","Australia"],"question":"From which country does the drink Tequila originate?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tommy Hilfiger","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Lauren","Calvin Klein","Michael Kors"],"question":"Which American fashion designer is famous for his red, white and blue sportswear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["West Germany","Argentina","England"],"question":"Which country won the 1970 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Mexico?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Injun Joe","incorrectAnswers":["Huckleberry Finn","Becky Thatcher","Tom Sawyer"],"question":"In the novel \"The Adventures of Tom Sawyer\", which character kills Dr. Robinson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Donkey, dog, cat and rooster","incorrectAnswers":["Horse, cow, pig and sheep","Mouse, rabbit, squirrel and fox","Duck, goose, swan and pigeon"],"question":"In the Grimm fairy tale \"Town Musicians of Bremen\", which group of aging animals sets out for Bremen to become musicians?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Prosper Mérimée","incorrectAnswers":["Maurice Leblanc","François-René de Chateaubriand","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Carmen'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Maya","incorrectAnswers":["Aztec","Minoans","Khmer"],"question":"What civilization built the ancient city of Chichen Itza?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Capri","incorrectAnswers":["Sicily","Corsica","Crete"],"question":"What small island is in the bay of Naples?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cupid","incorrectAnswers":["Valentine","Vixen","Rudolph"],"question":"Which of these is both one of Santa's reindeers and a mythological god of love?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Skopje","incorrectAnswers":["Yaounde","Sarajevo","Belgrade"],"question":"What is the capital city of North Macedonia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Marie Curie","incorrectAnswers":["Rosalind Franklin","Ada Lovelace","Grace Hopper"],"question":"Which female scientist was awarded two nobel prizes in the early 20th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mahershala Ali","incorrectAnswers":["Adam Driver","Sam Elliott","Richard E. Grant"],"question":"Who won the 2018 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Dr. Donald Shirley in Green Book?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"La-dee-da, la-dee-da.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Who's on first.\"","\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\"","\"I’m already pregnant. So, what other shenanigans could I get myself into?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Annie Hall'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Laughing gas","incorrectAnswers":["Mustard gas","Suffocating gas","Hot gas"],"question":"What is the non-technical term for nitrous oxide?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ursula K. Le Guin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Dispossessed'?","difficulty":"hard"},